

# **Curriculum Vitae for Jonathan Feinberg**

#### Personal information

Address: Pilestredet park 15 E-mail: jonathan@xal.no

0176 Oslo Phone: +47 93 21 44 74

Born: 28.04.1984

# **Summary**

I am a specialist in probability theory, statistics and machine learning with heavy focus on numerical programming and practical applications. I am highly analytical in my thinking and can quickly break down open ended complex problems into manageable components. At the same time I am also an experienced programmer, with expert level knowledge in the Python programming language.

### **Technical skills**

Frameworks Armadillo, GIS, Keras/Tensorflow, Matplotlib, NumPy/SciPy, Pandas,

PyMC, Scikit-Learn, Statsmodels, XGBoost

Languages Bash, C, C++, LaTFX, MATLAB, Python, R, RST/Markdown, Vim-

script, Regular Expression

Tools Continuous Integration, Version Control Systems, Documentation Ge-

neration

#### Education

2015 PhD in Mathematics from the Department of Mathematics, University

of Oslo.

Thesis written at Simula Research Laboratory: "Some Improvements and Applications and Non-intrusive Polynomial Chaos Expansions"

Supervised by Professor Hans Petter Langtangen.

2009 Master's degree in Modelling and Data Analysis, Department of

Mathematics, University of Oslo.

Thesis written at Norwegian Geotechinical Institute: "Threshold De-

finition of Early Warning Systems to Natural Hazards"

Supervised by Professor Bent Natvig.

2007 Bachelor's degree in Mathematics, Informatics and Technology, Uni-

versity of Oslo

# **Professional experience**

2016 -	Consultant at Expert Analytics
2016 –	Guest lecturer at the Department of Informatics, University of Oslo
2014 - 2015	Teaching Position at the Department of Informatics, University of Oslo
2014 - 2015	Private tutor at high school and undergraduate level at House of Math
2014 - 2015	Scientific Programmer for Simula Research Laboratory
2013 - 2014	Consultant at Kalkulo AS
2011 - 2014	Ph.D. student at Simula Research Laboratory
2009 - 2010	Research Assistant at Texas A&M University
2009 - 2009	Science Teacher at Smerud Medical Research
2008	Assistant Teacher at Department of Mathematics, University of Oslo
2007 - 2008	Student Ambassador at Public Relations and Events Office, University
	of Oslo
2007	Data Analyst at If P&C Insurance

## Languages

English Fluent

Norwegian Mother tongue

#### Personal skills

Communication I am able to convey research and condensed knowledge into a presen-

table and explainable form. Extensive experience as university lecturer

and teacher.

Planning I am a "Problem solver", able to see strengths and weaknesses of

proposed progress plans, grounded in fact-based thought.

Technology I have a high enthusiasm for learning and mastering new skills within

science, technology and programming.

### Some interests and hobbies

Personal Traveling, Gin tasting

Tech Bayesian Statistics/Probabilistic Modelling, Open Source Software,

Machine Learning, Global Optimization Algorithms, Python program-

ming

# **Extended descriptions of selected projects**

Activity NEC Oncoimmunity

Period 2016 – 2020

Role Senior Developer and Data Scientist

Staffing 20 Developers/Data Scientists/Bioinformaticians

Description Oncolmmunity develop bioinformatics software that has the ability

to empower precision cancer immunotherapy, improving the outlook for patients with late-stage disease. My role there was to develop machine-learning methods applied to genomic data for tumor immune profiling. The goal is to select optimal patients to be assigned to cancer

immunotherapy clinical trials.

Tools Python, Keras/Tensorflow, Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, XGBoost

Activity Statkraft
Period Summer 2016
Role Data Scientist
Staffing 3 developers

Description Statkraft is a leading company in hydropower internationally, and

Europe's largest generator of renewable energy. My role there was to explore the possibility of applying machine learning to parts of Statkraft's core business. In particular, we looked into various machine learning techniques that could be used to predict future market energy consume. The techniques included applying methods like statistical regression, time-series models, and artificial neural networks.

Tools Python, Keras/Tensorflow, Scikit-learn, Statsmodels

Activity Vipps AS
Period Fall 2020 -

Role Data Scientist/Advisor

Staffing 5 developers

Description Vipps is the leading service in Norway for person to person financial

transaction over mobile in Norway. I have been working on automating the detection of illegal transactions using machine learning, where my

role is the machine learning expert providing the methodology.

Tools Azure, SQL, XGBoost, Tensorflow

Activity Matlab to C++ converter

Period 2015 – 2016
Role Software developer
Staffing 2 developers

Description As part of an EU sponsored project, Simula Research Laboratory and

WesternGeco is collaborating to speed up the code translation step from Matlab to C++ using Armadillo. The approach involves creating a full parser that creates semi-automatic translations. I contributed as

the developer of the parser, and the structure of translation.

Tools Python, Armadillo, Sphinx

Activity Numpoly – Multivariate polynomials as NumPy datatype

Period 2019 –

Role Creator and Maintainer

Staffing 1 developer

Description Numpoly is an open source library for creating, manipulating polyno-

mial arrays. The library provides a subclass of numpy.ndarray implemented to represent polynomials as array element. As such it is fast and scales very well with the size of the coefficients, in addition to it

being compatible with most numpy functionalities.

https://github.com/jonathf/numpoly

Tools Python, NumPy

Activity Variable
Period Fall 2020
Role Advisor
Staffing 3 developers

Description Variable is a small startup focusing on quantifying climate risk. My

job was to teach the team on uncertainty quantification and help formulate the probabilistic building blocks needed to construct risk

models.

Tools Python, PyMC3